Guide to the John McLean Harrington Papers, 1760-1922
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John McLean Harrington papers 1760-1922
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Harrington, John McLean, 1839-1887.
7.1 linear feet Extent: 972 Items
harringtonj
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The John McLean Harrington Papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library between 1935-1950.
Biographical Note
Harrington was a teacher, surveyor, clerk, and sheriff, of Harnett Co., N.C.
Collection Overview
Correspondence, diary (1860), and other papers, of Harrington and of his father, James Stephens Harrington, state legislator. The correspondence includes information on public education in Guilford and Chatham counties, the Civil War, post-war activities of the Republican Party in North Carolina, and family matters. Includes weather reports for 1869-1870 and 1879-1882.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Republican Party (N.C.); Education -- North Carolina -- Chatham County; Education -- North Carolina -- Guilford County; Meteorology -- North Carolina -- Observations; Teachers -- North Carolina -- Correspondence; North Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Harrington, James Stephens
Separated Material
Broadside F-281: Election notice! :an election will be held on the second Thursday in November, the 9th day of the month, at the several precincts in the county of Cumberland for the following officers ...
Broadside F-306: A sheet of advertisements prepared by John McLean Harrington and possibly intended to be inserted into one of his publications
Related Material
Harrington published two handwritten newspapers during his career--The Young American (Jan.-Dec. 1858) and The Nation (April-Sept. 1858). Some of these newspapers form a part of his collection at Duke, while others are located in the Southern Historical Collection at UNC-Chapel Hill.
Typewritten transcriptions of the surviving issues have been prepared by Cambell University Libraries and are available at: http://www.lib.campbell.edu/harrington_papers/
Contents of Collection
- John McLean Harrington Papers, 1760-1922
  - Information folder (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1775-1869
  - Correspondence, 1870-1911 (Box 2)
  - Diary, 1859-1860
  - Weather book, 1869-1870
  - Weather chart book, 1879-1882
  - Legal Papers (Box 3)
  - Financial papers, 1782-1865
  - Financial papers, 1866-1922 (Box 4)
  - Writings and Speeches
  - Account books
  - Newspapers
  - Newspapers (Box 5)
  - Miscellany
  - Printed Material
  - Topical series
  - Topical Series (Box 6)
  - School and tax records (Opaperfolder Folder 1)
  - Harnett County Tax List (Opaperfolder Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Opaperfolder Folder 2)